Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1890-1995; Series III; 46; (112 boxes)
  - MEMOS & NOTEPADS
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 941-958)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 959-978)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 979-996)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 997-1008)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 1009-1021)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 1022-1040)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1041-1059)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1060-1075)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 1076-1102)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1103-1117)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1118-1125)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1126-1138)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1139-1147)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1148-1157)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1158-1178)
  - LOOSE NOTES
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1179-1186)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1187-1195)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1196-1204)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1205-1213)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1214-1223)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1224-1231)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1232-1237)
  - INVITATIONS
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1940s (Box 105, Folder 1238)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1950s (Box 105, Folder 1239)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1960s (Box 105, Folder 1240-1244)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1970s (Box 105, Folder 1245-1246)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1970s (Box 106, Folder 1247-1253)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1980s (Box 106, Folder 1254-1255)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, 1980s (Box 107, Folder 1256-1259)
    - Invitations to art exhibitions, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 1260-1263)
    - Invitations to social events, 1930s (Box 108, Folder 1264)
    - Invitations to social events, 1940s (Box 108, Folder 1265)
    - Invitations to social events, 1950s (Box 108, Folder 1266)
    - Invitations to social events, 1960s (Box 108, Folder 1267-1273)
    - Invitations to social events, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 1274-1277)
    - Invitations to social events, 1980s (Box 109, Folder 1278-1283)
    - Invitations to social events, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1284-1291)
    - Invitations to social events, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1292-1295)
  - PROGRAMS
    - General events, 1940s (Box 111, Folder 1296)
    - General events, 1950s (Box 111, Folder 1297)
    - General events, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 1298-1299)
    - General events, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 1300-1302)
    - General events, 1970s (Box 112, Folder 1303-1304)
    - General events, 1980s (Box 112, Folder 1305-1306)
    - General events, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 1307-1308)
    - Performances, 1930s (Box 112, Folder 1309)
    - Performances, 1940s (Box 112, Folder 1310)
    - Performances, 1950s (Box 112, Folder 1311)
    - Performances, 1960s (Box 112, Folder 1312-1313)
    - Performances, 1970s (Box 112, Folder 1314-1315)
    - Performances, 1970s (Box 113, Folder 1316-1321)
    - Performances, 1980s (Box 113, Folder 1322-1323)
    - Performances, 1980s (Box 114, Folder 1324-1326)
    - Performances, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 1327)
  - WHEELER/WESCOTT ART COLLECTION
    - Labeled files
      - "Appraisals of various works of art", 1967 (Box 115, Folder 1328)
        includes correspondence
      - "Art purchases", 1946-78, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1329)
      - "Art Works - MW - GW", 1966-79, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1330)
      - "GW - MW - Works of Art", 1939, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1331)
        includes card from Pierre Falké and photographs of India
      - "Monroe Wheeler's Collection", 1952-67, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1332)
      - "MW - Gifts to MMA", 1972-74, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1333)
      - "M.W. - Receipts for works or art borrowed by museums", 1939-47, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1334)
      - "MW - Works of Art - Ref.", 1966-71, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1335)
    - Loan and purchase documentation
      - Appraisals, 1960, 1977, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1336)
      - Lists of artworks, 1953, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1337)
      - Auction houses, 1977-80 (Box 116, Folder 1338)
      - Commercial art galleries, 1955-87, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1339)
      - Dartmouth College, Hopkins Center Art Galleries, 1967 (Box 116, Folder 1340)
      - Everson Museum of Art, 1983 (Box 116, Folder 1341)
      - Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco, 1974 (Box 116, Folder 1342)
      - Gallery of Modern Art, 1964 (Box 116, Folder 1343)
      - Grolier Club, 1945-78 (Box 116, Folder 1344)
      - Miami University Art Museum, 1981 Jan 9 (Box 116, Folder 1345)
      - Montclair Art Museum, 1975 (Box 116, Folder 1346)
      - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston & Los Angeles County Museum, 1960-61 (Box 116, Folder 1347)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1946-86, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1348-1353)
      - National Gallery, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1354)
      - New Jersey State Museum, 1969-85 (Box 116, Folder 1355)
      - Norton Gallery and School of Art, 1984-86 (Box 116, Folder 1356)
      - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1977 Dec (Box 116, Folder 1357)
      - Princeton University, 1952, 1981 (Box 116, Folder 1358)
      - Rutgers University, 1981-82 (Box 116, Folder 1359)
      - Trenton State College, 1986 May 10 (Box 116, Folder 1360)
      - University of Maryland, 1967 Mar 2 (Box 116, Folder 1361)
      - Unidentified exhibitions, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1362)
  - CLUB AND ORGANIZATIONAL AFFILIATIONS
    - Advisory Committee to the Art for Hospitals Program, 1958-59 (Box 117, Folder 1363)
    - Alliance Graphique Internationale, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1364)
    - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1958-76 (Box 117, Folder 1365)
    - American Society for Aesthetics, 1968 (Box 117, Folder 1366)
    - Americas Society, 1982-84 (Box 117, Folder 1367)
    - Art Dealer's Association of America, 1976 (Box 117, Folder 1368)
    - Arts Club of Chicago, 1960, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1369)
    - Asia Society, ca. 1958-60 (Box 117, Folder 1370)
    - Association Internationale de Bibliophilie, ca. 1965-77 (Box 117, Folder 1371)
    - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1967-83, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1372)
    - Coffee House, ca. 1965-88 (Box 117, Folder 1373-1374)
    - Folio Society, 1966 (Box 117, Folder 1375)
    - French Institute, 1950 (Box 117, Folder 1376)
    - Friends of the New Jersey State Museum, ca. 1968-85 (Box 117, Folder 1377)
    - Friends of the New Jersey State Museum, ca. 1968-85 (Box 118, Folder 1378)
    - Grolier Club, ca. 1927-87 (Box 118, Folder 1379-1381)
      Includes letters from: Denis Duveen; Jan Van Krimpen; Hyatt Mayor; Irving S. Old; Nelson Rockefeller; Charles Wrightsman
    - Hunterdon County Art Center, 1960-84 (Box 118, Folder 1382)
    - International Graphic Arts Society, 1952-78, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 1383-1385)
    - Melbourne Club, 1968 Aug 16 (Box 119, Folder 1386)
    - National Academy of Design, 1981 Jun 10 (Box 119, Folder 1387)
    - New York Art Director's Guild, 1949 (Box 119, Folder 1388)
      Includes catalog with essay by MW
    - New York Botanical Garden, 1979, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1389)
    - New York Genealogical and Biographical Society, 1953-85 (Box 119, Folder 1390-1391)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1964-85 (Box 119, Folder 1392)
    - Princeton University, Friends of the Art Museum, ca. 1973-77 (Box 119, Folder 1393)
    - Princeton University, Friends of the Princeton Library, 1976 (Box 119, Folder 1394)
    - Rutgers University, 1960-86, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1395-1396)
    - Thursday Evening Club, 1959-78, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1397)
    - Typophiles, 1979-86, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1398)
    - University of Maryland, President's Club, 1980-83 (Box 119, Folder 1399)
    - Unidentified organizations, 1977-85 (Box 119, Folder 1400)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Monroe Wheeler's personal files
      - "Announcement MW as Counsellor", 1967-68 (Box 120, Folder 1401)
      - "Arthritis", 1962 Nov 11 (Box 120, Folder 1402)
      - "Artists", 1958-60, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1403)
      - "Audubon Ballet (GW)", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1404)
        includes copy of "The Dream of Audubon"
      - Auden, W. H., 1982, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1405)
      - "Automobile", 1970 May 20 (Box 120, Folder 1406)
      - Berenson, Bernard and Kenneth Clark, 1971 Apr 12 (Box 120, Folder 1407)
      - Bonnard, Pierre, 1969-77 (Box 120, Folder 1408)
      - "Book Orders", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1409)
      - "Book Prices", 1957-75, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1410-1411)
      - "Buy" [Commercial order forms], 1974-82, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1412)
      - "Career", 1940-72, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1413)
      - "Career - MW", 1951-68, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1414)
      - "Cat Burglar", 1947, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1415)
      - "Change of Address", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1416)
      - "Condolence", 1966-95, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1417)
      - "Copyright", 1978 Jan 1 (Box 120, Folder 1418)
      - "Cuisine", 1967-80, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1419)
      - "John Crakanthorpe's Commonplace Book", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1420)
      - "Mrs. Richard Deutsch", 1975, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1421)
      - "Food", n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1422)
      - "410 - To Be Filed", 1941-56, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1423)
        includes correspondence, exhibition programs, and clippings
      - "France", 1949, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 1424)
      - "Francois", 1953-55, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1425)
      - Giraudoux, Jean, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1426)
        includes draft of English translation of "L'Apollon de Bellac"
      - Harrison, Wally, 1966, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1427)
      - "Marsden Hartley material assembled by MW in 1944", 1917-44, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1428)
      - "Household", 1975, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1429)
      - "Income", 1982, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1430)
      - Inge, William, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1431)
      - "Instructions for reaching Hay-Meadows", n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1432)
      - "Insurance", 1973-76, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1433)
      - "Japan", 1959-82, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1434)
      - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1950-86, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1435)
      - "W. Colston Leigh Lectures", 1963-64, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1436)
      - Loeb, Albert, 1972 Aug (Box 121, Folder 1437)
      - "Medicare", 1964-73, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1438)
      - "Mirth", n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1439)
      - "Monroe Wheeler", 1950-67, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1440)
      - "Monroe Wheeler - Retirement", 1967 (Box 121, Folder 1441)
      - MW - Biographical Notes, 1967-70, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1442)
      - "MW - C" [Career], 1939-66, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1443)
      - "MW's early publications", 1968, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 1444)
      - "MW's Fables", n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1445)
      - Obituaries, 1956-75, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1446)
      - "Poetry", n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1447)
      - Pohorilenko, Anatole, 1964-87, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1448)
      - Pomeroy, Ralph, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1449)
      - Rockefeller Family, 1947-79, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1450)
      - Rothschild, Phillippe, 1972, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1451)
      - Simmonds, Harvey, 1968-69, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1452)
      - "Miss Stewart's Princeton Bequest" [re: Marie Doro], 1961-65 (Box 122, Folder 1453)
      - "Stravinsky - 1972, NY City Ballet", 1972, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1454)
      - "Travel", 1958-70, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1455-1456)
      - "Typography", n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1457)
      - "Wills and Trusts" (Box 122, Folder 1458)
      - "Wit", n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1459)
      - Unlabeled, 1940, 1950, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1460)
    - General Items
      - Affidavits for travel: MW, 1953 (Box 123, Folder 1461)
        Includes set of fingerprints
      - "Anecdotes" notebook [blank], n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1462)
      - Annotated clippings, ca. 1956-82 (Box 123, Folder 1463)
      - Annotated postcards, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1464)
      - Annotated printed items, 1946-85 (Box 123, Folder 1465-1471)
      - Annotated printed items, 1946-85 (Box 124, Folder 1472)
      - Apartments in New York City, papers, 1957-84, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1473)
      - Art prospectuses, 1964, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1474)
      - "Baby's record" book, 1899 (Box 124, Folder 1475)
      - Biographical information: Ferruccio Busoni, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1476)
      - Biographical information: GW, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1477)
      - Biographical information: MW, 1984, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1478)
      - Birthday record book designed by Jan Van Krimpen, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1479)
      - Bishop, Elizabeth, listing in unidentified reference book, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1480)
      - Blotter pad, ca. 1930s (Box 124, Folder 1481-1482)
        Includes: notes, letter from Freddie Lee to Dorothee Nolan [1930 Nov 17], Harrison of Paris advertisements, catalog for GPL exhibition [1934], inventory of GPL's apartment in Villefranche [1928], cancelled checks, clippings, stationery, and photographs
      - Book covers and clipped book pages, 1939, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1483-1484)
      - Bookplates: GW, MW and Fred Wheeler (Box 124, Folder 1485)
      - Book prices, ca. 1950-70s (Box 125, Folder 1486-1490)
      - Book prospectuses, ca. 1940s-80s (Box 125, Folder 1491-1493)
      - Book prospectuses, ca. 1940s-80s (Box 126, Folder 1494)
      - Brochure: Berg Collection, New York Public Library, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1495)
      - "Business and social calendar of Monroe Wheeler in Rome", 1949 Mar 8 (Box 126, Folder 1496)
      - Business cards and name labels: MW (Box 126, Folder 1497)
      - Business cards and addresses (Box 126, Folder 1498-1501)
      - Calendar, 1978 (Box 126, Folder 1502)
      - Calendars of events, ca. 1960-85 (Box 126, Folder 1503)
      - Card, re: move to Hay Meadows, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1504)
      - Certificate for Régates Internationales, 1926 Mar 24 (Box 126, Folder 1505)
      - Christmas cards by MW, notebook binder, ca. 1950s (Box 127, Folder 1506)
      - Christmas cards by MW, loose, ca. 1937-67 (Box 127, Folder 1507-1509)
      - "Christmas records" notebook [blank], n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1510)
      - Civil Service appointment: MW, 1940 (Box 127, Folder 1511)
      - Colophon for book of Picasso prints, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1512)
      - Commercial items / product information, 1979-83, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1513)
      - Commercial order forms, not sent, 1964-80, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1514)
      - Commercial order forms, not sent, 1964-80, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 1515-1518)
      - Correspondence enclosures (Box 128, Folder 1519)
      - Cross leather portefeuille, monogrammed: Monroe Wheeler, ca. 1933-34 (Box 129, Folder 1520-1529)
        Contents:
        "A B": clippings, letter to MW from "Nelson" [1933 Nov 20]
        "C D": notes, letters to MW from Yvonne Ruth Danziger [1933 May 30] and from Marc Chagall [n.d.], letter of introduction for MW to Mrs. Kelloggs Fairbanks from "Katharine"
        "E F": receipt from Ernest Dalbret Antiques
        "G H": Christmas card to MW from Richard Halliday [1932 Dec 19]
        "J K": receipts, letter to MW from American Embassy in Japan [1933 Jan 13] containing permit to visit the palaces in Kyoto
        "L M": Dollar Steamship Lines information packet, letter to MW from Adelaide Lynes [1933 Apr 29] and from Jane [Mander?] [fragment, n.d.]
        "P Q": doctor's prescription and diet instructions
        "R S": receipt, letter to MW from S. H. de Roos [1934 Feb 20], from Francis Rose [1934 Feb 18], and from [E. Victors?] [1933 Sep 29]
        "V W": clippings re: Fear and Trembling, letter to MW from Barbara Wescott [n.d.], and from Glenway Wescott [1934, n.d.], photographs of Japan: MW by Japanese temple, MW & BW on board ship
      - Draft registration classification, 1943-44 (Box 130, Folder 1530)
      - Material re: Marie Doro, 1956-58 (Box 130, Folder 1531-1534)
        includes: correspondence, clippings, photographs, will, and notes
      - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1535)
        [retained for annotations]
      - Empty folder annotated by Pauline de Rothschild, 1967 Apr (Box 130, Folder 1536)
      - Encyclopedia Britannica certificate for MW as contributor, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1537)
      - Erratum sheet - unidentified book, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1538)
      - Fellowship information / forms, 1967, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1539)
      - Folder of items from 1920s, ca. 1921-28 (Box 130, Folder 1540)
        includes: diary pages, letter from "Mary", clippings, notes
      - Folder of items from 1930s, 1931-33 (Box 130, Folder 1541)
        includes: clippings, calling cards, and tickets
      - "Guest list and invitation to 'A Musical Evening' honoring Monroe Wheeler... in Bombay", 1956 Apr 24 (Box 130, Folder 1542)
      - Identification cards: GW & MW, 1920-87 (Box 130, Folder 1543)
      - International driving permit, 1952 (Box 130, Folder 1544)
      - Invitation: MW [blank], n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1545)
      - Material re: Jasna Polana, home of Seward and Basia Johnson, 1978, 1980 (Box 131, Folder 1546)
      - Juvenilia: The Literary and Scientific Club of Evanston, publications, 1914-17 (Box 131, Folder 1547)
      - Juvenilia: Evanston schools programs, 1909-17 (Box 131, Folder 1548)
      - Juvenilia: Yale Class Day booklet, 1914 Jun 15 (Box 131, Folder 1549)
      - Labels for artworks, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1550)
      - Lecture announcements, 1973, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1551)
      - Legion of honor information, 1951 (Box 131, Folder 1552)
        includes congratulatory letters from Fleur Cowles, William Inge, Stuart Preston, and Fred Wheeler
      - List of books belonging to MW, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1553)
      - List of Charles of the Ritz locations, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1554)
      - List of photograph collection, in French, in unidentified hand, 1897 Sep 16 (Box 131, Folder 1555)
      - List of real names of characters in Katherine Anne Porter's Hacienda (Box 131, Folder 1556)
      - Literary Items
        - Constant, Benjamin, letter to M. [Jean Pierre?] de la Cretelle, 1817 Aug 18 (Box 131, Folder 1557)
        - Symons, Arthur, letter to "Dear Sir", 1907 Feb 3 (Box 131, Folder 1558)
          with draft of response on verso
        - Whitman, Walt, transcriptions of letters to and from WW, 1935 (Box 131, Folder 1559)
          [from catalog of WW sale, by Sotheby & Co., 1935 May 13]
      - Literary passages and aphorisms, 1952, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1560)
      - Lottery tickets, 1974, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1561)
      - Maps and layout: Frank Lloyd Wright houses in Chicago (Box 131, Folder 1562)
      - Menus, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 131, Folder 1563)
      - Menus from Mouton Rothschild, 1965-67 (Box 131, Folder 1564-1565)
      - Menus from Mouton Rothschild, 1967-77, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 1566-1574)
      - Military papers: MW, 1918 (Box 132, Folder 1575)
      - "Monroe Wheeler's guest list for cocktails at the Hotel Continental, Salon Turque, in Paris", 1950 Apr 9 (Box 132, Folder 1576)
      - "MW's Typography" notebook binder, 1938-79, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1577)
      - Name plates for paintings, order information, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 1578)
      - Nametags: MW, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1579)
      - National Bureau of Standards color charts (Box 133, Folder 1580)
      - Newsletters, 1938-85, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1581)
      - Newsletters, 1938-85, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1582)
      - News releases, 1967-86, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1583)
      - Notes and clippings re: Elly Ney, ca. 1921 (Box 133, Folder 1584)
      - Notecards re: artworks, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1585)
      - Notecards re: "Die Kunst ist in Gefahr", n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1586)
      - Notecards: miscellaneous subjects, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1587)
      - Notes on MW's: appearance on Kenneth Clark's Civilization program, 1970 Nov (Box 133, Folder 1588)
      - Passports: MW, 1922-80s (Box 134, Folder 1589-1603)
      - Philadelphia Museum of Art Citation to MW, 1961 Jun 2 (Box 134, Folder 1604)
      - Pornography order forms and pages from physique magazines, ca. 1960s-80s (Box 134, Folder 1605-1606)
      - Set of postcards: "Paris - Santiago - Madrid - Toulouse - Paris, MW, GW, & GPL in a Ford - July - August 1933" (Box 135, Folder 1607-1609)
      - Recipes, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1610)
      - Registration receipt, France: MW, 1928 (Box 135, Folder 1611)
      - "Repasso di Ridimunho" [label for artwork?], n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1612)
      - Response card following GW's death, [1987] (Box 135, Folder 1613)
      - Resume: John Stevenson, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1614)
      - Rockefeller University information packet, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1615)
      - Scrapbook: re: Artists and exhibitions, ca. 1948-55
      - Sketches of the seal of New York [photocopy], n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1616)
      - State visit of Valery Giscard d'Estaing, information packet, 1976 May (Box 135, Folder 1617)
      - Stationery: MW, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1618)
      - Table cards, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 1619)
      - Tickets: Roundabout Theatre, 1982 (Box 135, Folder 1620)
      - Tour of homes booklet, 1968 May 20 (Box 135, Folder 1621)
        featuring Lloyd and Barbara Wescott & Glenway Wescott
      - Tourist card: Colombia, 1953 (Box 135, Folder 1622)
      - Travel information
        - Australia and the South Pacific (Box 136, Folder 1623)
        - Central and South America, 1953-81, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1624-1625)
        - China and Hong Kong (Box 136, Folder 1626)
        - France, 1947-79, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1627-1628)
        - Germany, 1921-58, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1629)
        - Greece, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1630)
        - India, 1953-59, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1631-1632)
        - Italy, 1950, 1974, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 1633)
        - Japan, 1955, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1634-1635)
        - Middle East, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1636)
        - Netherlands, 1977 (Box 137, Folder 1637)
        - Spain and Portugal, 1933, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1638)
        - Sri Lanka [Ceylon], 1953, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1639)
        - Switzerland, 1968, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1640)
        - Trinidad & Tobago, 1968-69, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1641)
        - United Kingdom, 1962-70, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1642)
        - United States, 1953-84, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1643-1644)
        - Yugoslavia, 1958-62, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1645)
        - Multiple destinations, 1952-82, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1646-1647)
        - General travel information, 1966-82, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1648)
        - Luggage labels, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1649)
        - Passport information, 1970-73, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1650)
      - Tulane University, information packet re: Anthropology Department, 1975 Sep (Box 138, Folder 1651)
      - Typesets and calligraphy sets: Monroe Wheeler (Box 138, Folder 1652)
      - Typography examples, 1932, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1653)
      - "Various documentary material of years gone by to remind Monroe of things in chronological order", ca. 1941-67 (Box 138, Folder 1654)
        Includes: letter to René de Messières [1951 Feb 20] letters from Ford Foundation [1962 Mar 8], Grolier Club [1962 Mar 8], International Graphic Arts Society [1957 Dec 30], Irving S. Olds [1955 Mar 2], Nelson A. Rockefeller [1947 Jul 15], Rutgers University [1967 Mar 29], letter from Nelson A. Rockefeller to Gardner Cowles [1960 Jun 29]
      - Vita: Edmund Wilson (Box 138, Folder 1655)
      - Voting information, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1656)
      - Information re: Lloyd and Barbara Wescott (Box 138, Folder 1657)
      - Information re: Ana and Fred Wheeler, ca. 1890-1962 (Box 138, Folder 1658)
      - Wheeler family geneaology notes, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1659)
      - Who's Who material: MW, 1960-84 (Box 138, Folder 1660-1661)
      - Wills, 1972, 1980, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 1662)
- Financial Papers, 1920-88; Series IV; 11.13; (27 boxes)